Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotksyism TAM.505
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism
2007-
TAM.505
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. (The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication.) The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of periodically captured websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. This collection contains periodically archived websites of (principally) Marxian inspired entities, including political parties, that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives. While the focus is on the United States, selected international sites, especially those documenting the history of these movements, are also archived. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of this collection (in the descriptive summary section at the top of the Guide) which will take you to the web archive, then go to the site list and then the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Contents
This web archive contains periodically archived websites of (principally) Marxian inspired entities, including political parties, that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives. While the focus is on the U.S., with a particular focus on New York City, selected international sites, especially those documenting the history of these movements, are also archived.
Classic Marxian doctrine advocates collective ownership of the means of production, to be achieved by the political struggle of the working class via political parties and labor unions, and the eventual withering away of the state.
For the purposes of this archive, Communist organizations are understood as those that supported or now align themselves with the ideology and politics of the former Soviet Union and the associated international Communist movement that arose in the aftermath of the Russian Revolution of 1917, or with the Chinese revolution (Maoism), or other schisms in the international Communist movement; Trotskyist organizations are those rooted in Leon Trotsky's critique of the Soviet Union, which he helped to found; Socialist organizations, including social democratic organizations (progressive organizations with socialism as an ultimate, if distant goal), include those rooted in the pre-1917 socialist movement, and reject the Communist ideal of a one-party state.
NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of this collection (in the descriptive summary section at the top of the Guide) which will take you to the web archive, then go to the site list and then the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism, along with other topically based web archives relating to labor and the left, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, as well as the history of labor and the left, principally in the United States, with a special concentration on New York City.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Communist Party of the United States of America.; Engels, Friedrich, 1820-1895; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1870-1924; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976.; Marx, Karl, 1818-1883.; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940.; Communism |x History.; Communism |z United States.; Communism.; Communist parties |z United States.; Communist parties.; Communists |z United States; Communists.; Marxism |x History.; Socialism |x History.; Socialism |z United States.; Socialism.; Socialist parties |z United States.; Socialist parties.; Socialists |z United States.; Socialists.; Soviet Union |x History.; Soviet Union |x Politics and government.; Trotskyism |x History.; Trotskyism |z United States.; Trotskyism.; Trotskyist parties |z United States.; Trotskyists.
- Communism, Socialism, Trotksyism Web Archive, 2007-
  - Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER), 07/29/2009-
  - Against the Current, Solidarity, 5/8/2011-11/5/2012
  - American Communism and Anticommunism: A Historian’s Bibliography and Guide to the Literature, 07/09/2009
  - Arguing the World | PBS Online, 08/31/2009
  - Brecht Forum, 07/31/2009-
  - Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism, 08/12/2009-
  - Communist Party of the United States of America, 05/10/2008-
  - CPGB Bibliography, 1/13/2010
  - CPUSA: Southern California Communist Party, 8/25/2010-1/20/2012
  - Demarcations Journal of Communist Theory and Polemic, 5/3/2012-
  - Democratic Socialists of America, 11/25/2008-
  - Dialectical Marxism: The Writings of Bertell Ollman, 07/31/2009-
  - Dissent Magazine, 5/5/2012-
  - Early American Marxism: A Repository of Source Material, 1864-1946, 09/23/09-
  - Encyclopedia of Trotskyism Online (ETOL), 12/09/08-
  - ernie124102, 4/14/2011-
  - Eugene V. Debs Foundation, 8/9/2010-
  - Facebook, Communist Party USA Notes, 8/11/2010-
  - Fight Imperialism Stand Together, 07/31/2009-
  - Freedom Road Socialist Organization, 2/25/2010-
  - Freedom Socialist Party (U.S.), 02/07/2007-
  - Holt Labor Library, 5/3/2012-
  - In Defence of Marxism, 12/11/2008-
  - International Bolshevik Tendency, 5/8/2011-
  - International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist), 11/25/2008-
  - International Publishers, 4/28/2012-
  - International Socialist Organization (U.S.), 11/20/2008-
  - Keep On Keepin' On, 7/8/2011-
  - Labor Upfront Newsletter, 05/05/2008-
  - League for the Revolutionary Party - Communist Organization for the Fourth International, 03/14/2009-
  - LeftShift.org, 04/20/2009-
  - Leon Trotsky Internet Archive, 12/10/2008-
  - Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal, 7/1/2011-
  - Lubitz TrotskyanaNet, 08/26/2009-
  - Maoist Internationalist Movements (MIM), 7/22/2010-7/10/2011
  - Marxism Leninism Today, 11/1/2010-
  - Marxist Education Press Publications, 5/1/2012-11/1/2012
  - Marxist-Humanist Initiative, 1/7/2010-
  - Marxists Internet Archive, 12/23/2008-
  - Monthly Review: An Independent Socialist Magazine, 03/26/2009-
  - National Committee to Reopen The Rosenberg Case, 07/26/2009-
  - New Politics, 5/5/2012-
  - New York State Communist Party, 8/11/2010-
  - News and Letters Committees, 03/14/2009-
  - Next Left Notes, 7/13/2011-
  - North-Atlantic Left Dialogue, 5/11/2011-
  - Northern California CCDS, 8/11/2010-
  - NYC Local of the Socialist Party USA, 08/08/2009-
  - NYCsocialist.org, 11/17/2010
  - Peace and Freedom Party, 07/31/2009-
  - People's World, 8/11/2010-
  - Phillip Bonosky, 11/9/2010-
  - Platypus Affiliated Society, 4/27/2012-
  - Progressive Labor Party, 07/29/2009-
  - PSLweb (Party for Socialism and Liberation), 08/02/2009-
  - Radical Women Freedom Socialist Party, 09/22/2007-
  - Religion and Socialism Commission, 5/4/2012-
  - Rethinking Marxism, 5/9/2011-
  - RevLeft, 12/13/2010-
  - Revolution Books (New York, NY), 09/22/2007-
  - Revolution: Voice of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, 8/13/2010-
  - Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, 09/22/2007-
  - Revolutionary Workers Group, 5/2/2011-
  - Science and Society, 5/1/2011-
  - Situations: Project of the Radical Imagination, 5/5/2012-
  - SocialDemocratsUSA.org, 04/08/2009-
  - Socialist Alternative, 03/14/09-
  - Socialist International, 5/4/2012-
  - Socialist Labor Party of America, 07/26/09-
  - Socialist Party USA, 09/23/07-
  - Socialist Viewpoint, 08/15/09-
  - Solidarity-US.org, 3/26/2010-
  - Spirit of Haymarket: Communist Party of Illinois Blog, 8/11/2010-
  - The Buckeye Socialist Alternative, 5/4/2011-11/05/2012
  - The League, 5/18/2011-
  - The Militant, 07/30/2009-
  - Trotsky.net, 12/10/2008-
  - Weather Underground FBI Report 1976, 08/09/2009
  - Whittaker Chambers, 7/15/2011-
  - Workers World, 07/31/2009-
  - Workers World Party, 07/31/2009-
  - World Socialist Web Site, 4/26/2012-
  - Young Communist League USA, 03/22/2009-
  - Young Democratic Socialists, 11/25/2008-
  - Young People's Socialist League, 09/23/2007-11/11/2010
  - Young People's Socialist League Reunion, 09/28/2007-5/8/2008
  - Youth for International Socialism, 12/09/2008-